Finding Aid for Z. Clark Dickinson papers, 1920-1959
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Z. Clark Dickinson papers 1920-1959
Dickinson, Z. Clark (Zenas Clark), 1889-
1 linear feet
851114 Aa 2
Correspondence concerning his economic views and the publication of his books and articles, manuscript biography of economics professor Fred M. Taylor, and miscellaneous articles and pamphlets.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Z. Clark Dickinson (donor no. 2649 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Z. Clark Dickinson was a professor of economics at the University of Michigan.
The collection consists of professional correspondence and a manuscript biography of economics professor Fred M. Taylor. Correspondents in the collection include Kenneth E. Boulding, Paul H. Douglas, John Maynard Keynes, Gunnar Myrdal, Bertrand Russell, George Santayana, and F. W. Taussig.
Subjects:
Economics.; Taylor, F. M. (Fred Manville), 1855-1932.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Economics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Contributors:
Boulding, Kenneth E. (Kenneth Ewart), 1910-1993; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Keynes, John Maynard, 1883-1946.; Myrdal, Gunnar, 1898-1987.; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.; Santayana, George, 1863-1952.; Taussig, Frank William, 1859-1940.
- Correspondence
  - 1920-1930 (Box 1)
    (include letter from John Maynard Keynes, March 12, 1924; from Bertrand Russell, August 27, 1923; from George Santayana, November 22, 1922; from F. W. Taussig, October 11, 1922, October 15, 1922, December 7, 1922)
  - 1931-1940 (Box 1)
    include letter from Paul H. Douglas, March 14, 1938; from Gunnar Myrdal, February 23, 1938, March 22, 1938, April 14, 1938, May 10, 1938; from F. W. Taussig, December 19, 1938
  - 1941-1950 (Box 1)
    (include letter from Kenneth E. Boulding, March 31, 1949; from Paul H. Douglas, December 21, 1949; from Gunnar Myrdal, April 28, 1942)
  - 1951-1959 (Box 1)
- Fred M. Taylor biography and related
  - Manuscript biography, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Preliminary draft, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Printed articles concerning Fred M. Taylor (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Papers concerning publication of "Compensating Industrial Effort" 1927-1937 (Box 1)
  - Printed articles by Z. Clark Dickinson (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous economic articles and pamphlets (Box 1)